<resources>
    <string name="app_name">World Tour</string>

    <string name="facts_links">http://www.softschools.com/facts/wonders_of_the_world/</string>
    <string name="facts_links2">http://www.thoughtco.com/seven-wonders-of-the-world-1435155/</string>

    <string name="facts_links3">http://www.unmuseum.org/7wonders/chunnel.htm</string>


    <string name="giza_content" formatted="true"> The Great Pyramid of Giza was built as a tomb for the Egyptian pharaoh Khufu. It took approximately 20 years to build and has three burial chambers inside.  When it was originally built (in approximately 2550 BC) it was almost 147 meters tall. Today, because of erosion, it is only about 139 meters tall.  Today, because of erosion, it is only about 139 meters tall. If you visit Egypt today you can enter the Great Pyramid through the Robbers’ Tunnel.</string>

    <string name="lighthouse_alexandria" formatted="true"> The Lighthouse of Alexandria was the first lighthouse in the world. Construction began in 290 BC and took twenty years to complete. When it was done it was the tallest building in the world at the time, except for the Great Pyramid. It was built on the island of Pharos, to help guide trade ships into its busy harbor at Alexandria, Egypt.  The lighthouse was damaged by several earthquakes and eventually became an abandoned ruin. In 1994 some of the remains of the lighthouse were discovered by French archaeologists in Alexandria\'s Eastern Harbor.</string>
    <string name="mausoleum_halicarnassus" formatted="true"> The Mausoleum at Halicarnassus was built by Artemisia after her husband Mausolus died. Mausolus and Artemisia had ruled over Halicarnassus and the region surrounding it for 24 years. When Mausolus died in 353 BC, Artemisia was reported to have been so broken-hearted she hired the most talented artists to create the most magnificent tomb in the world. The finished tomb was 147 feet tall and sat on a hill overlooking Halicarnassus. </string>
    <string name="colossus_rhodes" formatted="true"> The Colossus of Rhodes is a statue that was built on the Greek island of Rhodes between 292 and 280 BC. The statue was a depiction of the Greek Titan Helios and was meant to celebrate their victory over the ruler of Cyprus in 305 BC. At 98.4 feet high, the Colossus of Rhodes was one of the tallest statues of the ancient world. It only stood for 56 years until it was destroyed by an earthquake in 226 BC. When the ruler of Cyprus was defeated they left behind much of their equipment. The Rhodians sold the equipment and used the money to build the Colossus of Rhodes. </string>


    <string name="babylon_garden" formatted="true"> The Hanging Gardens of Babylon are thought to have been built in the ancient city of Babylon. Even though there is no proof that they actually existed, they are considered to be one of the Seven Wonders of the World. It is called the Hanging Gardens because the gardens were built high above the ground on multi-level stone terraces. The plants weren\'t rooted in the earth like a traditional garden. If it existed it was likely the most beautiful man-made gardens ever created.</string>
    <string name="temple_artemis" formatted="true"> The Temple of Artemis at Ephesus was built to honor Artemis, one of three maiden goddesses of Olympus. This temple is considered one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World. It was built in Ephesus (an ancient city), which today would be near Selcuk, Turkey. It had to be rebuilt at least three times due to fire, flood and a mob that was determined to destroy it. Each time it was rebuilt it became larger and even more beautiful and impressive.</string>
    <string name="statue_zeus" formatted="true"> The Statue of Zeus at Olympia was created by a sculptor named Phidias. It took him 12 years, from 430 to 422 BC, to complete the statue. Zeus was considered the king of the Greek gods and this magnificent statue was created to honor him. It was placed in the Temple at Olympia, a shrine to Zeus where Olympic Games took place every four years. The statue was destroyed by fire in the fifth century A.D.</string>


    <string name="section_format">Hello World from section: %1$d</string>
    <string name="title_activity_natural_wonders">NaturalWonders</string>
    <string name="cn_tower_text">The CN Tower (French: Tour CN) is a 553.3 m-high (1,815.3 ft) concrete communications and observation tower in downtown Toronto, Ontario, Canada. Built on the former Railway Lands, it was completed in 1976, and held the record for the world\'s tallest free-standing structure for 32 years from 1975–2007 and was the world\'s tallest tower until 2009 being overtaken by Burj Khalifa and Canton Tower, respectively. It is now the third tallest tower in the world and remains the tallest free-standing structure in the Western Hemisphere, a signature icon of Toronto\'s skyline, attracting more than two million international visitors annually</string>
    <string name="empire_state_text">The Empire State Building is a 102-story skyscraper on Fifth Avenue between West 33rd and 34th Streets in Midtown, Manhattan, New York City. It has a roof height of 1,250 feet (381 m), and with its antenna included, it stands a total of 1,454 feet (443.2 m) tall.[7] Its name is derived from the nickname for New York, the Empire State. The Empire State Building stood as the world\'s tallest building for nearly 40 years, from its completion in early 1931 until the topping out of the original World Trade Center\'s North Tower in late 1970. Following the September 11 attacks in 2001, the Empire State Building was again the tallest building in New York, until One World Trade Center reached a greater height in April 2012. The Empire State Building is currently the fifth-tallest completed skyscraper in the United States and the 35th-tallest in the world. It is also the fifth-tallest freestanding structure in the Americas. When measured by pinnacle height, it is the fourth-tallest building in the United States.</string>
    <string name="golden_gate_text">The Golden Gate Bridge is a suspension bridge spanning the Golden Gate, the one-mile-wide (1.6 km) strait connecting San Francisco Bay and the Pacific Ocean. The structure links the American city of San Francisco, California – the northern tip of the San Francisco Peninsula – to Marin County, carrying both U.S. Route 101 and California State Route 1 across the strait. The bridge is one of the most internationally recognized symbols of San Francisco, California, and the United States. It has been declared one of the Wonders of the Modern World by the American Society of Civil Engineers. The Frommer\'s travel guide describes the Golden Gate Bridge as possibly the most beautiful, certainly the most photographed, bridge in the world. It opened in 1937 and was, until 1964, the longest suspension bridge main span in the world, at 4,200 feet (1,280 m)</string>
    <string name="itaipuDam_text">Itaipu Dam is a hydroelectric dam located on the border of Paraguay and Brazil. The resource used to run this dam is the Parana River, which forms a natural barrier between the two countries. The plan for a hydro-generating plant, using the Parana River as its source of energy, began in the 1960s. In the 1980s the dam was officially opened. The American Society of Civil Engineers considered the Itaipu Dam to be such an amazing achievement that they listed it as one of the Seven Wonders of the Modern World.</string>
    <string name="delta_works">Because the Netherlands is one of the most low-lying countries in the world, its people have struggled every time a storm raises the water levels. As far back as the first century A.D. the inhabitants of this area have attempted to protect themselves from the devastation the rising water levels have caused. The Zuiderzee was originally a shallow bay in the North Sea. It was about 30 miles wide and reached 60 miles inland. Although it was a large bay it was only about 15 feet deep. Every time there was a storm, dikes failed and the land was flooded.</string>
    <string name="panama_canal">The Panama Canal connects the Pacific and Atlantic Oceans. It is a 48 mile canal that is important for international maritime trade. Construction of the canal began in 1881by France, but there were engineering problems and too many people were dying due to disease. Construction stopped until the US took over in 1904. They took 10 years to complete the canal. The canal allowed ships to travel between the two oceans more safely and in half the time. In 1999 the Panamanian government took control of the canal. The Panama Canal is one of the Seven Wonders of the Modern World.</string>
    <string name="victory_falls">Victoria Falls is one of the Seven Natural Wonders of the World and the major waterfall on the Zambezi River in Africa. It is famous for being the largest waterfall in the world, in the wet season. The African people who live around the falls call it Mosi-oa-Tunya which means smoke that thunders. The water makes a roaring noise as it falls over the cliff and down into the Zambezi River below. A cloud of water vapor is always seen around the falls.</string>
    <string name="barrier_reef">The Great Barrier Reef is one of the seven wonders of the natural world. It is the world\'s largest coral reef system and the only living structure seen from space. The coral reef is like a city of separate homes made by tiny sea creatures called coral polyps.</string>
    <string name="rio_de_janeiro">The Harbor of Rio de Janeiro is one of the ‘Seven Natural Wonders of the World\'. It is located in the country of Brazil, South America. It is world famous for being the world\'s largest bay, having mountains that come down almost to the water\'s edge and for an enormous statue that looks down on the city and harbor from one the mountain peaks.</string>
    <string name="northern_lights">At the North and South Magnetic Poles of our planet Earth, we see the sky light up, flash and shimmer. We call this effect an aurora. In the northern hemisphere it is called the Aurora borealis, also known as the Northern Lights. In the southern hemisphere, it is called Aurora australis, also known as the Southern Lights.</string>
    <string name="grand_canyon">The Grand Canyon is in the United States of America. Millions of years ago, instead of a deep canyon, this area was a giant flat slab of layered rock that we call the Colorado Plateau. Rain and melted snow forming the Colorado River have flowed over this plateau for millions of years, cutting into the rock surface and forming the Grand Canyon.</string>
    <string name="mt_everest">The tallest mountain on land in our world is part of the Himalayan Alps and called Mount Everest. The local Tibetan people, called Sherpa, call it Chomolungma which means Mother Goddess of the Universe and in Nepal, it is called Sagarmatha which means Goddess of the Sky. Mt. Everest is located in the mountain range bordering the countries of Nepal and Tibet.</string>
    <string name="paricutin_volcano">Paricutin volcano, also known as \'Volcan de Paricutin\' is located in the state of Michoacan, Mexico. It is one of the Seven Natural Wonders of the World. It is famous because it is the youngest volcano to form in the Northern Hemisphere, developing in a farmer\'s cornfield. The lava flow from the volcano smothered the Mexican villages of Paricutin and San Juan Parangaricutiro.</string>


</resources>
