<resources>
    <string name="app_name">World Tour</string>

    <string name="facts_links">http://www.softschools.com/facts/wonders_of_the_world/</string>
    <string name="giza_content" formatted="true"> The Great Pyramid of Giza was built as a tomb for the Egyptian pharaoh Khufu. It took approximately 20 years to build and has three burial chambers inside.  When it was originally built (in approximately 2550 BC) it was almost 147 meters tall. Today, because of erosion, it is only about 139 meters tall.  Today, because of erosion, it is only about 139 meters tall. If you visit Egypt today you can enter the Great Pyramid through the Robbers’ Tunnel.</string>

    <string name="lighthouse_alexandria" formatted="true"> The Lighthouse of Alexandria was the first lighthouse in the world. Construction began in 290 BC and took twenty years to complete. When it was done it was the tallest building in the world at the time, except for the Great Pyramid. It was built on the island of Pharos, to help guide trade ships into its busy harbor at Alexandria, Egypt.  The lighthouse was damaged by several earthquakes and eventually became an abandoned ruin. In 1994 some of the remains of the lighthouse were discovered by French archaeologists in Alexandria\'s Eastern Harbor.</string>
    <string name="mausoleum_halicarnassus" formatted="true"> The Mausoleum at Halicarnassus was built by Artemisia after her husband Mausolus died. Mausolus and Artemisia had ruled over Halicarnassus and the region surrounding it for 24 years. When Mausolus died in 353 BC, Artemisia was reported to have been so broken-hearted she hired the most talented artists to create the most magnificent tomb in the world. The finished tomb was 147 feet tall and sat on a hill overlooking Halicarnassus. </string>
    <string name="colossus_rhodes" formatted="true"> The Colossus of Rhodes is a statue that was built on the Greek island of Rhodes between 292 and 280 BC. The statue was a depiction of the Greek Titan Helios and was meant to celebrate their victory over the ruler of Cyprus in 305 BC. At 98.4 feet high, the Colossus of Rhodes was one of the tallest statues of the ancient world. It only stood for 56 years until it was destroyed by an earthquake in 226 BC. When the ruler of Cyprus was defeated they left behind much of their equipment. The Rhodians sold the equipment and used the money to build the Colossus of Rhodes. </string>


    <string name="babylon_garden" formatted="true"> The Hanging Gardens of Babylon are thought to have been built in the ancient city of Babylon. Even though there is no proof that they actually existed, they are considered to be one of the Seven Wonders of the World. It is called the Hanging Gardens because the gardens were built high above the ground on multi-level stone terraces. The plants weren\'t rooted in the earth like a traditional garden. If it existed it was likely the most beautiful man-made gardens ever created.</string>
    <string name="temple_artemis" formatted="true"> The Temple of Artemis at Ephesus was built to honor Artemis, one of three maiden goddesses of Olympus. This temple is considered one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World. It was built in Ephesus (an ancient city), which today would be near Selcuk, Turkey. It had to be rebuilt at least three times due to fire, flood and a mob that was determined to destroy it. Each time it was rebuilt it became larger and even more beautiful and impressive.</string>
    <string name="statue_zeus" formatted="true"> The Statue of Zeus at Olympia was created by a sculptor named Phidias. It took him 12 years, from 430 to 422 BC, to complete the statue. Zeus was considered the king of the Greek gods and this magnificent statue was created to honor him. It was placed in the Temple at Olympia, a shrine to Zeus where Olympic Games took place every four years. The statue was destroyed by fire in the fifth century A.D.</string>


    <string name="section_format">Hello World from section: %1$d</string>


</resources>
